Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records ALBA.019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: General Files, 1940-2006; 155527
  - Spain: Elections, 1976-1977, 1979; 155648 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Spain: Friends of National Spain, "Exposure of the Secret Plan to Establish a Soviet in Spain", undated; 155647 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Spain: Gobierno Republica Espanola, Paris, undated, 1962-1963; 155646 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Spain: Guerrillas, undated, 1941, 1944; 155645 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Spain: Labor Unrest, ca.1965-1975; 155644 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Spain: "The People's Front," Outline, undated; 155643 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Spain: People's Socialist Party (P.S.P.), Bulletin, 1975; 155642 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, undated, 1971-1976; 155641 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Ana, Marcos, 1964-1971; 155640 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Des Anciens Internes Politiques et Resistants--Bulletin, 1976-1981; 155639 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Carabanchel 10, undated, 1973-1974; 155638 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Children's Vacation Fund, undated; 155637 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Clippings, undated, 1952-1974; 155636 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Comision Ejecutiva Permante Latino Americana, 1960-1961; 155635 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Commissie hulp aan Spanje, 1977-1978; 155634 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conference, 1960; 155633 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conference, 1971; 155632 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conferences, undated, 1953-1965; 155631 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conferences--Latin America, undated, 1961; 155630 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Correspondence, undated, 1948, 19591960; 155629 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Correspondence--Appeals, undated, 1959, 19711974; 155628 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Defense Fund--Booklet, undated; 155627 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Duchess of Medina-Sidonia, 1968, 1970; 155626 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Grimau, Julian, 1963; 155625 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, International Committee of the Comisiones de Solidaridad de Catalunya, 1976; 155624 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, O'Casey, Sean, undated, 1960; 155623 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Pena, Leoncio, 1959-1964; 155622 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Prison--Oviedo, 1962; 155621 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Reports and Statements, undated, 1954-1963, 1971-1973; 155620 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Speech-Pete Smith, 1958; 155619 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, United Nations--Appeal, 1960; 155618 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Spain: Politics, notebook, undated; 155617 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Spain: Publications, Spanish Newsletter, Feb 1972-Oct 1972; 155616 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Spain: Protests, Nov 1976; 155615 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Spain: Students, undated, 1952, 1967-1976; 155614 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Spain: "Twenty-Five Years of Military Involvement", 1975; 155613 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Spain: United Furniture Workers of America, 1948; 155612 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Spain: Women, Union de Mujeres Espanolas, 1947; 155611 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Spain: Workers' Commission, 1973-1976; 155610 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Spain: Spanish-American Defense Committee, undated; 155609 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Spanish Civil War, American Writing and the: Richard Bjornson, undated, 1976; 155608 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Spanish Civil War: "Americanos en el Hospital de las Brigadas Internacionales de Benicassam", 1997; 155607 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Spanish Civil War: Bibliographies, undated, 1979; 155606 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Spanish Civil War: Bibliography, articles (1937-1954), undated; 155605 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Spanish Civil War: Collectors' Catalogues, undated, 1997; 155604 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Spanish Civil War: Death Benefit Claims, Correspondence, 1939, 1942-1949; 155603 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Spanish Civil War: Ebro, Battle of--Map, undated; 155602 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Spanish Civil War: Fuerte de Carchuna, 1938; 155601 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Spanish Civil War: Irish and Irish-Americans, undated; 155600 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Spanish Civil War: Jewish Volunteers, undated, 1966, 1976; 155599 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Ambulance Drivers, undated; 155598 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, American participants, 1969; 155597 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, undated; 155596 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Miscellaneous, undated; 155595 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Missing, undated; 155594 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Mortality, undated, 1974; 155593 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Mortality (Canadian Volunteers), 1974; 328960 (Box 21, Folder 9A)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Prisoners, undated, 1978; 155592 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Sailing, undated; 155591 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Sailing (return), undated; 155590 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Veterans, undated, 1939; 155589 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Spanish Civil War: Manuscript, undated; 155588 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Spanish Civil War: Memoirs, Drafts, undated; 155587 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Spanish Civil War: " Postscript in Blood", undated; 155586 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners, German, undated; 155585 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners of War, "Diplomatic Protection", undated; 155584 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners of War, Manuscript I, undated; 155583 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners of War, Manuscript II, undated; 155582 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Spanish Civil War: Recruitment, book chapter, undated; 155581 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Spanish Civil War: Research File, articles, undated, 1937-1940, 1962-1969; 155580 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Spanish Civil War: Songs, undated; 155579 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Spanish Civil War: Songs, The Songs of the Lincoln Brigade--Correspondence, 1944; 155578 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Spanish Civil War: Union de Excombatientes de la Guerra de Espana, undated; 155577 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Spanish Civil War: "A View from a Midwest Campus," by Robert Perlman (typescript, with original SCW button), 1982; 155576 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Spanish Labor Alliance, undated, 1966-1967; 155575 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Spanish Labor Alliance: Report, 1966; 155574 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc., undated, 1960-1980; 155573 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Spanish Refugee Appeal, undated; 155572 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Spanish Refugees, undated, 1940, 1950-1958; 155571 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Spanish Refugees: Chile: Timon(publication), undated; 155570 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Spanish Refugees: Committee of Spanish Refugees of Chile, undated; 155569 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Spanish Refugees: Cuba, 1947, 1949; 155568 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Spanish Refugees: France, undated, 1946; 155567 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Spanish Refugees: Ministry of Labor and Social Assistance, undated; 155566 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Spanish Sailors, Committee to Save, undated, 1957; 155565 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Starini, Joseph: Deportation, 1947; 155564 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Steck, Bob, undated, 1996-1998; 155563 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Student Papers, 1979-1994; 155562 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Student Papers: "American and Red to the Core: The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War," K. Unger (Yale), 1998; 155561 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Student Papers: "American Veterans of the Spanish Civil War," K. Jacobson. (with oral history transcripts: Clarence Forester, Martin Maki, Joe Travascio), 1996; 155560 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Student Papers: Brandeis University, 1974; 155559 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Szurek, Alexander: Autobiography, The Shattered Dream, undated, 1974, 1989; 155558 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Theater: Boyington, Mike, Dancer in Madrid(script), undated; 155557 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Thompson, Bob, undated, 1949-1968, 1981; 155556 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Tyler, Hamilton: The Pilgrimage of Evan Cade, I, undated; 155555 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Tyler, Hamilton: The Pilgrimage of Evan Cade, II, undated; 155554 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Twin Cities Cultural Workers Association, 1984; 155553 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee, undated, 1940-1941; 155552 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee: Bulletins, 1940; 155551 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee: Committee for the Release of International Volunteers in French and Spanish Prison Camps, undated, 1941; 155550 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee: Rescue Ship Mission, undated; 155549 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Committee for a Democratic Spain, undated, 1974-1978; 155548 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - United States Dept. of Justice: Foreign Agents Registration Act, Correspondence, 1948; 155547 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Van der Schelling, Bart, 1993, 1996; 155546 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Histories of, ca.1940-1984; 155545 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - VALB: Histories of, drafts, undated; 155544 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Veterans: Rehabilitation, ca.1941; 155543 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Veterans' Rights, 1943, 1956, 1971-1985; 155542 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Vietnam War, undated, 1967-1969; 155541 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Volunteer: General, undated, 1958, 1975-1990; 155540 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Volunteer: Correspondence, undated, 1973-1990; 155539 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Volunteer: "Cracker Barrel", undated, 1990-1991; 155538 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Volunteer: Materials, Unused, 1991; 155537 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Volunteer: Materials for Inclusion, undated, 1983-1988; 155536 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Websites re: International Brigades, undated, 1996; 155535 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Weinberg, Gerald, 1943; 155534 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Weissman, Irving: Botwin File, 1972-1994; 155533 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Wellman, Saul, undated, 1969-1987; 155532 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Wildegans, Gustav, 1973-1979; 155531 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Wolff, Milton, undated, 1947, 1970-1995; 155530 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - World War II: Veterans, Civilian Defense, 1941-1943; 155529 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Zlatovski, George: An Anti Hero of Our Time, undated, 2000; 155528 (Box 22, Folder 32)
- Series III: Scrapbooks (Oversize), 1939-1953; undated; 155524
  This series consists of two scrapbooks. One scrapbook contains official correspondence dating from 1939 to 1953. It includes fundraising letters signed by Lillian Hellman, Paul Robeson, Vincent Sheean, and David McKelvy White, among others. The second scrapbook contains broadsides, invitations, tickets, stamps, and brochures for dances, rallies, fundraisers and other VALB events. These scrapbooks provide an overview of VALB's early years.
  - Correspondence, undated, 1939-1953; 155526 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera, undated; 155525 (Box 23, Folder 2)